<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Softstream]]></title>
  <link href="http://softstream.eu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://softstream.eu/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-02T10:47:04+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://softstream.eu/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wear Yourself]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Wear+Yourself"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Wear Yourself</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Wear Yourself</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The task was to create extension to the existing ASP.NET application that will allow:</p>

<ul>
<li>Allow customers to create custom designs for t-shirts, sweatshirts and jackets with WYSIWYG editor</li>
<li>Provide clipart management subsystem</li>
<li>Integrate extension with existing order processing system</li>
<li>Provide integration with <em>printing machinery</em></li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Warehouse Workflows Automation]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Warehouse+Workflows+Automation"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Warehouse Workflows Automation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Warehouse Workflows Automation</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>American-based provider of home movie and video game rental services, originally through video rental shops.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer suffered from huge amounts of paperwork. The task was to automate warehouse workflows for maximal efficiency. Main objectives were including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Centralize warehouses data</li>
<li>Accounting of product transferring between warehouses</li>
<li>Reporting</li>
<li>Forecasting and inventory optimization</li>
<li>Integration with barcode scanners</li>
</ul>


<p>As a solution team offered:</p>

<ul>
<li>Single database with enabled replication for maximal performance of endpoint warehouses</li>
<li>Web interface was designed to replace the existing desktop application and papers</li>
<li>Using <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_optimization">mathematical optimization</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_theory">game theory</a> methods automate forecasting and analysis</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>All paperwork was eliminated</li>
<li>Productivity was achieved using keyboard-only user interface</li>
<li>Time needed for daily routines of warehouse personnel was reduced by 300%</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telemedicine Process Automation]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Telemedicine+Process+Automation"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Telemedicine Process Automation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Telemedicine Process Automation</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>A Supplier of Mobile Cardiac Outpatient Telemetry that provides the next-generation ambulatory cardiac monitoring service with beat-to-beat, real time analysis, automatic arrhythmia detection and wireless ECG transmission.
It helps clinicians prevent morbidity, mortality and disability with rapid diagnosis and treatment of patients with cardiovascular disease.</p>

<h2>Objectives and Solution</h2>

<p>The project was to automate the process of ECG signal decoding transmitted via phone landlines and integrate solution with existent patient monitoring system.
Signal could be recorded in noisy place with distortions caused by landlines equipment. Also target was to successfully process no less than 70% of all records.</p>

<ul>
<li>Applied numerical analysis to the problem and created mathematical model for signal processing</li>
<li>Integrated with existing patient monitoring system through XML Web Services technology</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Successfully designed and implemented self adaptive demodulator algorithm</li>
<li>Through reverse engineering technical documentation for supported cardiac monitors was re-defined and corrected</li>
<li>Application UX was designed for maximum personnel efficiency and fully supports control via keyboard</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[System of Credits Issuing]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/System+of+Credits+Issuing"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/System of Credits Issuing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>System of Credits Issuing</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Being a National Lending Associates, Inc. (NLA) Customer company provides customized loan, credit management and tuition receivables support to lenders and schools. Its offerings include web based programs designed to help institutions ensure compliance with all Federal Truth- in- Lending disclosure requirements.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The project was to improve and extend the functionality of the System of Credits Issuing with further information export to the loan servicing firms. Project was running on legacy software technologies and had no documentation, contacts with previous development team were lost.</p>

<ul>
<li>Recover and document technical design, core business processes and requirements</li>
<li>Automate deployment and versioning processes</li>
<li>Improve maintainability and stability of the project</li>
<li>Perform project reengineering inlucluding:

<ul>
<li>Redundant components removal</li>
<li>Replacement of legacy software components with newer alternatives</li>
<li>Appliance of best software architecture practices where appropriate</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Extend the functionality of the credit issuing business-processes</li>
<li>Optimize overall system performance</li>
<li>Establish basement for software as a service solution that could be used by partner organizations</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Working in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_delivery">continious delivery</a> manner allowed to complete more than 150 major features, improvements and optimizations</li>
<li>By providing high quality and flexible services the customer established new partnership contacts which allowed to start moving system toward <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_as_a_service">SaaS</a> model</li>
<li>Project duration – 1 year and work is still in progress</li>
<li>Project volume – 3000 men/hrs and work is still on</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recruiting Agency System]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Recruiting+Agency+System"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Recruiting Agency System</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Recruiting Agency System</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Large recruiting agency specializing in personnel recruiting, holding of appraisals and training. Company is represented in all regions around Ukraine.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The goal was to refine existing tools and utilities and create a portal globally accessible from all departments and offices across the country. Team was assigned to design integrated working environment that will fully automate document flow and reporting.
The key requirement was high system responsiveness achieved with extensive usage of AJAX and splitting of database data.</p>

<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Close communication with customer and personnel simplified requirements gathering and refinement</li>
<li>Active usage of codegeneration boosted the efficiency of the team</li>
<li>Project high quality and evolution capability was ensured by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_factory">Software Factory</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real Estate System Upgrade]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Real+Estate+System+Upgrade"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Real Estate System Upgrade</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Real Estate System Upgrade</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>One of the largest provider of Errors and Omissions Insurance and Risk Management Services. We have protected real estate professionals since 1996 and today protect more than 75,000 nationwide.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer wanted to increase speed of the new functionality development. Along with this task there was a problem with compatibility of existing legacy software with new operating systems.</p>

<p>Team was assigned to research possibilities of integration of Visual Basic based software with Microsoft .NET technologies.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Recovered mission critical parts of technical documentation using reverse engineering techniques</li>
<li>Integrated .NET with existing software using ActiveX technology</li>
<li>The part of Visual Basic modules was converted to COM visible .NET assemblies</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Successfully mixed new and legacy software bits</li>
<li>With new vision for architectural design increased productivity of development team</li>
<li>Once again company was able to quickly adopt to evolving business and market</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RFID Tracking Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/RFID+Tracking+Solution"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/RFID Tracking Solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>RFID Tracking Solution</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>A leading vendor of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio-frequency_identification">RFID</a> tracking solutions.
It provides services for large corporations, law enforcement and government organizations, offering high performance technology solutions including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Asset Tracking</li>
<li>Evacuation &amp; Emergency Management</li>
<li>Student Accountability</li>
<li>Event Metrics and Social Media</li>
</ul>


<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>A sophisticated system comprised of a number of desktop applications. Solution needed to be analyzed and re‐engineered.</p>

<p>Additionally the team task was to integrate with third party systems and services and allow clients to use system on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_as_a_service">SaaS</a> basis.</p>

<p>Another challenge was to ensure solution scalability.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Developed several cross-platform client applications based on Mono Framework(Xamarin), MonoTouch,  MonoDroid technologies</li>
<li>Scalability and high availability was reached using cloud services such as Windows Azure and Amazon Services (EC2)</li>
<li>Service oriented architecture backed by WCF, REST and Web Services</li>
<li>Reports were powered by Microsoft Reporting Services</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Development resulted in highly configurable and extensible system</li>
<li>Moving solution to the Cloud helped substantially decrease customer operating expenses</li>
<li>Continuous process improvement allowed to minimize time to market for new features</li>
<li>Created the suite of web, desktop and mobile applications hosted on Microsoft, Android and IOS platforms</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Personalized Photo Albums]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Personalized+Photo+Albums"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Personalized Photo Albums</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Personalized Photo Albums</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Printing company offering its services for universities, colleges and schools in the United States of America. It is offering creation of personalized collegiate books, calendars, postcards, business and greeting cards.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The aim of the project was to create top quality, personalized and digitally-printed memorabilia targeted to college students, sports fans, and university alumni, that meant following tasks:</p>

<ul>
<li>Enable educational institutions to create custom products by customization of the backgrounds, logos, images, icons and photos</li>
<li>Products should be digitally printed on-demand, thereby allowing for complete customization options</li>
<li>Integrate with number of online printing services allowing users to choose printing provider</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Rich user experience was achieved by investments in the latest technologies and most advanced production equipment</li>
<li>With browser-based software, there is nothing to download and install</li>
<li>Integration with social networks allowed easy sharing of photo albums between end customers</li>
<li>Customers have complete control over product creation and personalization</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Order Processing Automation]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Order+Processing+Automation"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Order Processing Automation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Order Processing Automation</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Customer is a manufacturer of trucks, buses and construction equipment, that also supplies marine and industrial drive systems, and financial services with focus on quality, safety and environmental care. Founded more than 80 years ago, a solid position and reputation worldwide has been built up over the decades.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The main goal of the project was to make it easier to select and purchase details, ensuring simplicity of navigation, establishing maximum speed for searching and filtering. Retail agents can sell goods at different stores.</p>

<p>Sales department needed to have a software that:</p>

<ul>
<li>Creates customized brochures</li>
<li>Provides advanced product filtering based on user preferences</li>
<li>Automates order processing</li>
<li>Provides data sync point for retail agents</li>
<li>Bridges existing reporting software with the new order processing subsystem</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>On time and on budget</li>
<li>Efficient and modern UI</li>
<li>Successfully migrated huge amount of data from papers to the central database</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marketing Materials Management]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Marketing+Materials+Management"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Marketing Materials Management</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Marketing Materials Management</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>A global financial services company which provides investment banking, asset management and wealth management services for private, corporate and institutional clients worldwide, as well as retail clients.</p>

<p>It is one of the largest banks in the world. It is considered the world&#8217;s second largest manager of private wealth assets, a leading provider of retail banking and commercial banking services.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer wanted to replace a number of existing business processes related to the bank marketing materials.<br/>
The team was assigned to create the web based portal that will act as a central point for:</p>

<ul>
<li>Marketing materials management and exchange</li>
<li>Cart and order management</li>
<li>Assets storage</li>
<li>User management</li>
<li>Personalized email subscriptions</li>
</ul>


<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Orders processing and shopping cart based on Pageflex Storefront</li>
<li>Created Pageflex extension that mirrors and extends functionality of Campaign Manager</li>
<li>Created number of custom pages integrated into Pageflex to administer and control new extension</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Fully automated PDF generation workflow which now is used throughout all the bank departments in more than 50 countries around the world</li>
<li>Created customizable order processing workflow</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marketing Management Platform]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Marketing+Management+Platform"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Marketing Management Platform</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Marketing Management Platform</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>A leading provider of Distributed Marketing Management Platforms (DMMP). By integrating best-in-class marketing and technology provides clients with a faster, more effective way to grow and manage their marketing initiatives through use of proprietary platform.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The project was to create content management for Customer retail agents. System should  collect financial information and allow to place orders of customized documents.</p>

<p>Major tasks:</p>

<ul>
<li>Integrate ASP.NET based web application with <a href="http://www.pageflex.com/Products/Pageflex-Server.aspx">Pageflex Server</a> and <a href="http://www.pageflex.com/Products/Pageflex-Storefront.aspx">Pageflex Storefront</a></li>
<li>Create <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Business_rule_management_system">business rule management system</a> that will process financial information</li>
<li>Build complex products with use of document actions and custom steps</li>
<li>Provide automation of order placement using Storefront API</li>
<li>Develop a bunch of PageFlex extensions</li>
<li>Modify default Storefront web pages</li>
</ul>


<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Created highly-customizable Form-Filling forms utilizing jQuery and jSINI</li>
<li>To make process more streamlined created plugins for Pageflex Studio</li>
<li>Integrated membership and setup synchronization with external systems</li>
<li>Provided Single Sign On subsystem</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Solution significantly decreased time needed to prepare and complete single order</li>
<li>Created flexible data import subsystem for importing large bulks of data (hundreds of MBytes)</li>
<li>With system roll-out all the redundancy in Customer workflows was eliminated</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MMORPG Game Server]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/MMORPG+Game+Server"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/MMORPG Game Server</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>MMORPG Game Server</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>A Russian startup company.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer had a vision of a next generation <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Massively_multiplayer_online_role-playing_game">MMORPG</a> (massive multiplayer online role playing game) but it had no expertise in client-server multiplayer games with high numbers of online users.</p>

<p>Our research and development group was asked to prepare general architectural recommendations and build a prototype of the game server.</p>

<p>The main requirements for the single game server instance were:</p>

<ul>
<li>High availability (no less than 99.999%)</li>
<li>Ability to handle up to 10 thousand simultaneous connections</li>
<li>Minimal network load. Users with 3G connection of 2048 Kbytes/sec should be able to play.</li>
</ul>


<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Created custom binary protocol on top of UPD with delivery guarantee support for critical messaging scenarios</li>
<li>Network load minimized by sending only &#8220;deltas&#8221; - personalized chunks of data that actually changed.</li>
<li>High availability was assured by a Microsoft IIS web farm with load balancing</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>First version of working prototype was able to handle more than 2000 connections</li>
<li>Custom protocol that unified ideas of UDP broacasting and multicasting allowed significantly decrease load on network</li>
<li>Plugin based architecture weakened dependencies between server components and streamlined development process</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leasing Services Provider]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Leasing+Services+Provider"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Leasing Services Provider</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Leasing Services Provider</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Fast growing company that operates in North America and provides leasing services including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Building equipment and materials</li>
<li>Machinery</li>
<li>Human resources</li>
</ul>


<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer wanted to replace existing manually edited and processed spreadsheets with web site globally accessible by staff and customers.
The main idea was to prevent time losses due to continuous phone calls and manual filling in of invoices and work log reports.
The system should allow customers to control budget and expenses through reports and approval workflow.</p>

<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Usage of <strong>our own</strong> patterns and practices reduced risks and made system more fault-tolerant</li>
<li>The latest technologies stack has shortened time needed for full development cycle to two calendar months</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Management System]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Learning+Management+System"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Learning Management System</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Learning Management System</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Company provides an award-winning, comprehensive learning management system for the coordination of e-learning, classroom training, assessment and records management. Product is used on a daily basis by directors of training, e-learning and human resources and provides solutions to their common challenges.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer wanted to revise existent solution functionality and move it to the Web. New system had to be horizontally scalable.</p>

<p>Another challenge was to provide highly configurable and flexible licensing system that will give customer an ability to sell or lend certain parts of the system to partner organizations.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Project was envisioned as a suite of web and desktop applications hosted on Microsoft platform</li>
<li>The project team involved in all stages of product development and research activities with product owner providing a business analysis, requirements specification and support management</li>
<li>Developed auto testing framework</li>
<li>Automated deployment and versioning processes</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Project exists for more than 2 decades</li>
<li>Team provides support of Microsoft .NET powered version for more than 5 years</li>
<li>High level of automation guarantees high quality of software releases</li>
<li>Effective collaboration of distributed team is ensured by agile practices</li>
<li>In 2013 project reached volume of more than 50 man/years</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Insurance Plans Management]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Insurance+Plans+Management"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Insurance Plans Management</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Insurance Plans Management</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>The largest health care insurer in the mid-Atlantic region a member of Blue Cross Blue Shield Association.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The Company faced the daunting challenge of keeping more than three million members informed about a myriad of insurance plans with frequently changing benefits.
The Customer envisioned an automated, print-on-demand solution for producing member kits that would integrate with its existing ordering system. By replacing a manual process requiring a large inventory of loose sheets and an outside installment facility, Customer sought to increase efficiency and reduce the waste associated with dated materials while improving the accuracy, quality and image of its marketing kits.</p>

<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Created a highly customized and efficient process for online ordering and on-demand print production</li>
<li>The solution enabled Customer to eliminate an entire warehouse, avoid the waste associated with obsolete materials and reduce its postage costs and call center volumes</li>
<li>The solution has generated an enthusiastic response from insurance brokers and customers</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Healthcare Center]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Healthcare+Center"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Healthcare Center</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Comfortsleep</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Healthcare center located in New Jersey.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer had legacy application that partially implemented existing workflows. System was inconvenient and not flexible enough for further support.</p>

<p>The problem was to reengineer legacy software, automate and rewise existing workflows including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Implement assets order management</li>
<li>Automate equipment trasfering between warehouses</li>
<li>Create CRM-like system that bridges between physicians patients and insurance companies</li>
<li>Integrate with equipment usage monitoring third party systems</li>
</ul>


<p>Along with automation there was a task to increase effectiveness and perfromance of the new system.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Several webportals were developed and cross integrated</li>
<li>Extensibility was ensured by service-oriented architecture</li>
<li>Existing data was migrated by means of custom built tool</li>
<li>Replication of data across warehouses significantly increased overral performance</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Perfect mix of local involvement and remote communication among team members located in different development locations</li>
<li>Appliance of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_integration">continuous integration</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unit_testing">unit testing</a> practices significantly reduced costs spent on
testing</li>
<li>UX design and implementation time was greatly reduced with the assistance rich component framework</li>
<li>Customer has a long-term plans to extend functionality onto mobile platform</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health Insurer Reporting]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Health+Insurer+Reporting"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Health Insurer Reporting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Health Insurer Reporting</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>The largest health care insurer in the mid-Atlantic region a member of Blue Cross Blue Shield Association.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Initially every department in company was obligated with monthly and weekly report generation in form of excel file. All reports, data aggregation and monitoring activities were made manually. Customer wanted to automate generation and processing of the data spreadsheets and centralize data storage.
Along with data processing there was a task to integrate with existing storefront system.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Imported all historical data via Microsoft Integration Services</li>
<li>Web interface built on top of Microsoft technologies stack</li>
<li>Integration of the web site with Active Directory allowed to implement existing access policies</li>
<li>Report generation was automated and centralized using Microsoft Reporting Services</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>New system is installed and successfully functioning for many years</li>
<li>RUP methodology with XP features approach</li>
<li>Data centralization and processing automation helped customer to conform changing business needs</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brewery Marketing Activities]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Brewery+Marketing+Activities"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Brewery Marketing Activities</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Brewery Marketing Activities</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>One of the largest American-owned breweries.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The application had to be utilized to place orders for promotional items. Orders may be placed by authorized associates via friendly web-based user interface. The application implies the back-end which is utilized by the application administrators to manage orders, users and other specific information.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Application was built on top of ASP.NET</li>
<li>Integrated with online purchase service to make it possible to process payment in various ways</li>
<li>Employed Microsoft Reporting Services to generate sales reports</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Development boosted by 3rd party components library</li>
<li>Successfully ported rich UI experience onto tablet devices</li>
<li>Customer saved resources that were spent on marketing activities</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Airlines Luggage Tags]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Airlines+Luggage+Tags"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Airlines Luggage Tags</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Airlines Luggage Tags</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>A large airline based in California, with operations throughout the western United States and western Canada, as well as into Mexico.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Company wanted to create online service that will allow customers to create custom luggage tags. Along with this service customer required:</p>

<ul>
<li>Order management backend software</li>
<li>Integration with several printing companies</li>
</ul>


<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>ASP.NET powered site</li>
<li>Extensive use of JavaScript</li>
<li>Printing assets preprocessing and generation done with scheduler controlled Windows Services</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Using the homegrown rapid prototyping framework first working prototype was launched in 1 week</li>
<li>Cross-browser WYSIWYG editor written fully in JavaScript</li>
<li>Service is W3C standards compliant</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
