<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: team outsourcing | Softstream]]></title>
  <link href="http://softstream.eu//categories/team-outsourcing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://softstream.eu/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-11T11:24:11+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://softstream.eu/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Telemedicine Process Automation]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Telemedicine+Process+Automation"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Telemedicine Process Automation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Telemedicine Process Automation</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>A Supplier of Mobile Cardiac Outpatient Telemetry that provides the next-generation ambulatory cardiac monitoring service with beat-to-beat, real time analysis, automatic arrhythmia detection and wireless ECG transmission.
It helps clinicians prevent morbidity, mortality and disability with rapid diagnosis and treatment of patients with cardiovascular disease.</p>

<h2>Objectives and Solution</h2>

<p>The project was to automate the process of ECG signal decoding transmitted via phone landlines and integrate solution with existent patient monitoring system.
Signal could be recorded in noisy place with distortions caused by landlines equipment. Also target was to successfully process no less than 70% of all records.</p>

<ul>
<li>Applied numerical analysis to the problem and created mathematical model for signal processing</li>
<li>Integrated with existing patient monitoring system through XML Web Services technology</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Successfully designed and implemented self adaptive demodulator algorithm</li>
<li>Through reverse engineering technical documentation for supported cardiac monitors was re-defined and corrected</li>
<li>Application UX was designed for maximum personnel efficiency and fully supports control via keyboard</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Healthcare Center]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Healthcare+Center"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Healthcare Center</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Comfortsleep</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Healthcare center located in New Jersey.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer had legacy application that partially implemented existing workflows. System was inconvenient and not flexible enough for further support.</p>

<p>The problem was to reengineer legacy software, automate and rewise existing workflows including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Implement assets order management</li>
<li>Automate equipment trasfering between warehouses</li>
<li>Create CRM-like system that bridges between physicians patients and insurance companies</li>
<li>Integrate with equipment usage monitoring third party systems</li>
</ul>


<p>Along with automation there was a task to increase effectiveness and perfromance of the new system.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Several webportals were developed and cross integrated</li>
<li>Extensibility was ensured by service-oriented architecture</li>
<li>Existing data was migrated by means of custom built tool</li>
<li>Replication of data across warehouses significantly increased overral performance</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Perfect mix of local involvement and remote communication among team members located in different development locations</li>
<li>Appliance of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_integration">continuous integration</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unit_testing">unit testing</a> practices significantly reduced costs spent on
testing</li>
<li>UX design and implementation time was greatly reduced with the assistance rich component framework</li>
<li>Customer has a long-term plans to extend functionality onto mobile platform</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brewery Marketing Activities]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Brewery+Marketing+Activities"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Brewery Marketing Activities</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Brewery Marketing Activities</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>One of the largest American-owned breweries.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The application had to be utilized to place orders for promotional items. Orders may be placed by authorized associates via friendly web-based user interface. The application implies the back-end which is utilized by the application administrators to manage orders, users and other specific information.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Application was built on top of ASP.NET</li>
<li>Integrated with online purchase service to make it possible to process payment in various ways</li>
<li>Employed Microsoft Reporting Services to generate sales reports</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Development boosted by 3rd party components library</li>
<li>Successfully ported rich UI experience onto tablet devices</li>
<li>Customer saved resources that were spent on marketing activities</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Airlines Luggage Tags]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Airlines+Luggage+Tags"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Airlines Luggage Tags</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Airlines Luggage Tags</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>A large airline based in California, with operations throughout the western United States and western Canada, as well as into Mexico.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Company wanted to create online service that will allow customers to create custom luggage tags. Along with this service customer required:</p>

<ul>
<li>Order management backend software</li>
<li>Integration with several printing companies</li>
</ul>


<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>ASP.NET powered site</li>
<li>Extensive use of JavaScript</li>
<li>Printing assets preprocessing and generation done with scheduler controlled Windows Services</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Using the homegrown rapid prototyping framework first working prototype was launched in 1 week</li>
<li>Cross-browser WYSIWYG editor written fully in JavaScript</li>
<li>Service is W3C standards compliant</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
