<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Full cycle | Softstream]]></title>
  <link href="http://softstream.eu//categories/full-cycle/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://softstream.eu/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-14T21:16:17+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://softstream.eu/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recruiting Agency System]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Recruiting+Agency+System"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Recruiting Agency System</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Recruiting Agency System</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Large recruiting agency specializing in personnel recruiting, holding of appraisals and training. Company is represented in all regions around Ukraine.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The goal was to refine existing tools and utilities and create a portal globally accessible from all departments and offices across the country. Team was assigned to design integrated working environment that will fully automate document flow and reporting.
The key requirement was high system responsiveness achieved with extensive usage of AJAX and splitting of database data.</p>

<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Close communication with customer and personnel simplified requirements gathering and refinement</li>
<li>Active usage of codegeneration boosted the efficiency of the team</li>
<li>Project high quality and evolution capability was ensured by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_factory">Software Factory</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RFID Tracking Solution]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/RFID+Tracking+Solution"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/RFID Tracking Solution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>RFID Tracking Solution</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>A leading vendor of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio-frequency_identification">RFID</a> tracking solutions.
It provides services for large corporations, law enforcement and government organizations, offering high performance technology solutions including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Asset Tracking</li>
<li>Evacuation &amp; Emergency Management</li>
<li>Student Accountability</li>
<li>Event Metrics and Social Media</li>
</ul>


<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>A sophisticated system comprised of a number of desktop applications. Solution needed to be analyzed and re‐engineered.</p>

<p>Additionally the team task was to integrate with third party systems and services and allow clients to use system on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_as_a_service">SaaS</a> basis.</p>

<p>Another challenge was to ensure solution scalability.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Developed several cross-platform client applications based on Mono Framework(Xamarin), MonoTouch,  MonoDroid technologies</li>
<li>Scalability and high availability was reached using cloud services such as Windows Azure and Amazon Services (EC2)</li>
<li>Service oriented architecture backed by WCF, REST and Web Services</li>
<li>Reports were powered by Microsoft Reporting Services</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Development resulted in highly configurable and extensible system</li>
<li>Moving solution to the Cloud helped substantially decrease customer operating expenses</li>
<li>Continuous process improvement allowed to minimize time to market for new features</li>
<li>Created the suite of web, desktop and mobile applications hosted on Microsoft, Android and IOS platforms</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leasing Services Provider]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Leasing+Services+Provider"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Leasing Services Provider</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Leasing Services Provider</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Fast growing company that operates in North America and provides leasing services including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Building equipment and materials</li>
<li>Machinery</li>
<li>Human resources</li>
</ul>


<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer wanted to replace existing manually edited and processed spreadsheets with web site globally accessible by staff and customers.
The main idea was to prevent time losses due to continuous phone calls and manual filling in of invoices and work log reports.
The system should allow customers to control budget and expenses through reports and approval workflow.</p>

<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Usage of <strong>our own</strong> patterns and practices reduced risks and made system more fault-tolerant</li>
<li>The latest technologies stack has shortened time needed for full development cycle to two calendar months</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Management System]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Learning+Management+System"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Learning Management System</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Learning Management System</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Company provides an award-winning, comprehensive learning management system for the coordination of e-learning, classroom training, assessment and records management. Product is used on a daily basis by directors of training, e-learning and human resources and provides solutions to their common challenges.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer wanted to revise existent solution functionality and move it to the Web. New system had to be horizontally scalable.</p>

<p>Another challenge was to provide highly configurable and flexible licensing system that will give customer an ability to sell or lend certain parts of the system to partner organizations.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Project was envisioned as a suite of web and desktop applications hosted on Microsoft platform</li>
<li>The project team involved in all stages of product development and research activities with product owner providing a business analysis, requirements specification and support management</li>
<li>Developed auto testing framework</li>
<li>Automated deployment and versioning processes</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Project exists for more than 2 decades</li>
<li>Team provides support of Microsoft .NET powered version for more than 5 years</li>
<li>High level of automation guarantees high quality of software releases</li>
<li>Effective collaboration of distributed team is ensured by agile practices</li>
<li>In 2013 project reached volume of more than 50 man/years</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
