<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: project outsourcing | Softstream]]></title>
  <link href="http://softstream.eu//categories/project-outsourcing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://softstream.eu/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-14T21:10:52+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://softstream.eu/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Leasing Services Provider]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Leasing+Services+Provider"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Leasing Services Provider</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Leasing Services Provider</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Fast growing company that operates in North America and provides leasing services including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Building equipment and materials</li>
<li>Machinery</li>
<li>Human resources</li>
</ul>


<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer wanted to replace existing manually edited and processed spreadsheets with web site globally accessible by staff and customers.
The main idea was to prevent time losses due to continuous phone calls and manual filling in of invoices and work log reports.
The system should allow customers to control budget and expenses through reports and approval workflow.</p>

<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Usage of <strong>our own</strong> patterns and practices reduced risks and made system more fault-tolerant</li>
<li>The latest technologies stack has shortened time needed for full development cycle to two calendar months</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning Management System]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Learning+Management+System"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Learning Management System</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Learning Management System</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Company provides an award-winning, comprehensive learning management system for the coordination of e-learning, classroom training, assessment and records management. Product is used on a daily basis by directors of training, e-learning and human resources and provides solutions to their common challenges.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer wanted to revise existent solution functionality and move it to the Web. New system had to be horizontally scalable.</p>

<p>Another challenge was to provide highly configurable and flexible licensing system that will give customer an ability to sell or lend certain parts of the system to partner organizations.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Project was envisioned as a suite of web and desktop applications hosted on Microsoft platform</li>
<li>The project team involved in all stages of product development and research activities with product owner providing a business analysis, requirements specification and support management</li>
<li>Developed auto testing framework</li>
<li>Automated deployment and versioning processes</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Project exists for more than 2 decades</li>
<li>Team provides support of Microsoft .NET powered version for more than 5 years</li>
<li>High level of automation guarantees high quality of software releases</li>
<li>Effective collaboration of distributed team is ensured by agile practices</li>
<li>In 2013 project reached volume of more than 50 man/years</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Insurance Plans Management]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Insurance+Plans+Management"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Insurance Plans Management</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Insurance Plans Management</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>The largest health care insurer in the mid-Atlantic region a member of Blue Cross Blue Shield Association.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The Company faced the daunting challenge of keeping more than three million members informed about a myriad of insurance plans with frequently changing benefits.
The Customer envisioned an automated, print-on-demand solution for producing member kits that would integrate with its existing ordering system. By replacing a manual process requiring a large inventory of loose sheets and an outside installment facility, Customer sought to increase efficiency and reduce the waste associated with dated materials while improving the accuracy, quality and image of its marketing kits.</p>

<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Created a highly customized and efficient process for online ordering and on-demand print production</li>
<li>The solution enabled Customer to eliminate an entire warehouse, avoid the waste associated with obsolete materials and reduce its postage costs and call center volumes</li>
<li>The solution has generated an enthusiastic response from insurance brokers and customers</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Health Insurer Reporting]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Health+Insurer+Reporting"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Health Insurer Reporting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Health Insurer Reporting</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>The largest health care insurer in the mid-Atlantic region a member of Blue Cross Blue Shield Association.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Initially every department in company was obligated with monthly and weekly report generation in form of excel file. All reports, data aggregation and monitoring activities were made manually. Customer wanted to automate generation and processing of the data spreadsheets and centralize data storage.
Along with data processing there was a task to integrate with existing storefront system.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Imported all historical data via Microsoft Integration Services</li>
<li>Web interface built on top of Microsoft technologies stack</li>
<li>Integration of the web site with Active Directory allowed to implement existing access policies</li>
<li>Report generation was automated and centralized using Microsoft Reporting Services</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>New system is installed and successfully functioning for many years</li>
<li>RUP methodology with XP features approach</li>
<li>Data centralization and processing automation helped customer to conform changing business needs</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
