<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: custom model | Softstream]]></title>
  <link href="http://softstream.eu//categories/custom-model/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://softstream.eu/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-23T10:59:59+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://softstream.eu/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alex]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recruiting Agency System]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Recruiting+Agency+System"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Recruiting Agency System</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Recruiting Agency System</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Large recruiting agency specializing in personnel recruiting, holding of appraisals and training. Company is represented in all regions around Ukraine.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The goal was to refine existing tools and utilities and create a portal globally accessible from all departments and offices across the country. Team was assigned to design integrated working environment that will fully automate document flow and reporting.
The key requirement was high system responsiveness achieved with extensive usage of AJAX and splitting of database data.</p>

<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Close communication with customer and personnel simplified requirements gathering and refinement</li>
<li>Active usage of codegeneration boosted the efficiency of the team</li>
<li>Project high quality and evolution capability was ensured by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_factory">Software Factory</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real Estate System Upgrade]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Real+Estate+System+Upgrade"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Real Estate System Upgrade</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Real Estate System Upgrade</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>One of the largest provider of Errors and Omissions Insurance and Risk Management Services. We have protected real estate professionals since 1996 and today protect more than 75,000 nationwide.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>Customer wanted to increase speed of the new functionality development. Along with this task there was a problem with compatibility of existing legacy software with new operating systems.</p>

<p>Team was assigned to research possibilities of integration of Visual Basic based software with Microsoft .NET technologies.</p>

<p>Solution:</p>

<ul>
<li>Recovered mission critical parts of technical documentation using reverse engineering techniques</li>
<li>Integrated .NET with existing software using ActiveX technology</li>
<li>The part of Visual Basic modules was converted to COM visible .NET assemblies</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Successfully mixed new and legacy software bits</li>
<li>With new vision for architectural design increased productivity of development team</li>
<li>Once again company was able to quickly adopt to evolving business and market</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Personalized Photo Albums]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Personalized+Photo+Albums"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Personalized Photo Albums</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Personalized Photo Albums</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Printing company offering its services for universities, colleges and schools in the United States of America. It is offering creation of personalized collegiate books, calendars, postcards, business and greeting cards.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The aim of the project was to create top quality, personalized and digitally-printed memorabilia targeted to college students, sports fans, and university alumni, that meant following tasks:</p>

<ul>
<li>Enable educational institutions to create custom products by customization of the backgrounds, logos, images, icons and photos</li>
<li>Products should be digitally printed on-demand, thereby allowing for complete customization options</li>
<li>Integrate with number of online printing services allowing users to choose printing provider</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>Rich user experience was achieved by investments in the latest technologies and most advanced production equipment</li>
<li>With browser-based software, there is nothing to download and install</li>
<li>Integration with social networks allowed easy sharing of photo albums between end customers</li>
<li>Customers have complete control over product creation and personalization</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Order Processing Automation]]></title>
    <link href="http://softstream.eu/project/Order+Processing+Automation"/>
    <updated>2013-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://softstream.eu/project/Order Processing Automation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Order Processing Automation</h1>

<h2>Customer</h2>

<p>Customer is a manufacturer of trucks, buses and construction equipment, that also supplies marine and industrial drive systems, and financial services with focus on quality, safety and environmental care. Founded more than 80 years ago, a solid position and reputation worldwide has been built up over the decades.</p>

<h2>Objective and solution</h2>

<p>The main goal of the project was to make it easier to select and purchase details, ensuring simplicity of navigation, establishing maximum speed for searching and filtering. Retail agents can sell goods at different stores.</p>

<p>Sales department needed to have a software that:</p>

<ul>
<li>Creates customized brochures</li>
<li>Provides advanced product filtering based on user preferences</li>
<li>Automates order processing</li>
<li>Provides data sync point for retail agents</li>
<li>Bridges existing reporting software with the new order processing subsystem</li>
</ul>


<h2>Project highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li>On time and on budget</li>
<li>Efficient and modern UI</li>
<li>Successfully migrated huge amount of data from papers to the central database</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
